《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
大家喊他食人魔
The guys call him The Ogre.
他是个连环杀手
He's a serial killer.
不管凶手是谁  他就是个禽兽
Whoever did this, he's a monster.
他下个杀的人的血就在我手上
The blood of his next victim is on my hands!
如果你不放手  那就可能会是小莱的血
If you don't drop it, that blood could be Lee's.
因为食人魔会报复调查他的警察
Because The Ogre retaliates against any cop who investigates
杀害他们所爱的人
and kills the people they love.
刺伤阿尔弗雷德的那个人  他还在哥谭
The man who stabbed Alfred, he's in Gotham.
你想让我帮你找他
And you need my help to find him.
谁派你去的
Who sent you?
你希望我去告诉邦德斯洛你发现他了吗
You want me to tell Bunderslaw that you're onto him?
本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再加工制成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
Silence    木浅薰    爵士年代蓬蓬裙    DustD    草草
Kallen    艹明    最可爱的小胖子
你似乎离家有点远啊
You look far from home.
离他远点
Get away from him.
否则呢
Or what?
随你便
Whatever.
来
Come on.
你回去过吗
Did you go back?
回过了  警察赶到了
Yeah. The cops are there.
然后呢
And?
然后什么
你以为呢
What do you think?
他从五楼窗户掉下去的  他死了
He fell out of a five-story window. He's dead.
你为什么要那么做
Why'd you do it?
他跟我们说了我们想知道的事  说了邦德斯洛
He told us what we wanted. He told us about Bunderslaw.
你根本没必要杀他
You didn't have to go and kill the guy!
当然有必要  因为我们一走
Yes, I did! 'Cause the moment we'd left,
他就会通知他的老大
he was gonna go tell his boss!
顺带说一句  那人还是你的公司的
Who works for you, by the way.
他就是想杀掉我的人
He's the one who tried to kill me,
他还想杀掉你的管家
who tried to kill your butler...
还有可能是杀害你爸妈的凶手
who probably killed your parents.
我救了你一命
I saved your life.
再说了  你也想杀了他
Besides... you wanted to do it, too.
只是没胆而已
You just didn't have the guts.
-等等  -回家吧
- Wait...! - Just go home.
我们还得查明谁是邦德斯洛  以及他的目的
We still have to find out who Bunderslaw is and what he wants.
你是说你得去查吧
You mean you do.
你真以为这事结束了吗
You really think this is over?
他会来追杀我们的
He's gonna come after us.
那接下来怎么做
So what's next?
他的保险箱
His safe.
什么
What?
韦恩集团的每一个高级主管
Every senior executive at Wayne Enterprises
在办公室里都有一个保险箱
has a safe in their office.
邦德斯洛的秘密肯定就藏在里面
A-Any secrets Bunderslaw has, that's where they'll be.
用钥匙还是密码
Key or combination?
钥匙  我爸以前就有一把
Key. My dad had one.
那他可能会随身携带
He'll probably keep it on him, then.
想办法让我靠近他  我就能把钥匙偷来
Figure out a way to get me close, and I'll steal it.
行吗
Can you do that?
应该行吧
I think so.
今晚发生的事
And what happened tonight,
不要告诉任何人
you tell no one.
不能告诉戈登警探
Not your buddy Detective Gordon,
也不能告诉你的管家
not your butler.
谁也不能说
No one.
哥谭
第一季  第二十集
饿得慌
宝宝
草草
测试物品上的刺孔与被害人身上的一致
Punctures on test subject are consistent with those on the victim,
表明了凶手惯用右手
indicating the killer was right-handed.
好吃
Yum.
汤普金斯在哪
Where's Thompkins?
戈登警探  汤普金斯医生说我可以随意
Detective Gordon, Dr. Thompkins said I was free
用这个房间  她人很好
to use this room. She's very nice.
她和之前那位验尸官不一样
She's not like the old medical examiner.
爱德  直接说她在哪
Ed, just tell me where she is.
别打谜语
No riddles.
在家里  她回家了
Home. She went home.
希望你能找到她
Hope you find her.
吉姆
Jim?
吉姆  是你吗
Jim, is that you?
吉姆
两通未接电话
我不剥你皮算你走运
You're lucky I don't skin you.
走吧
Go on.
-慢点说  -小莱  我没事
- I... slow down. - Lee, please.
从头再说一次
Start over.
你接手的这件案子  这个死去的女人
This case you caught, the dead woman,
是被连环杀手所杀吗
she was murdered by a serial killer?
没错  他杀了十几个女人  可能更多
Yes. Who's killed a dozen women, maybe more.
洛布是故意把这案子交给你的吗
And Loeb gave you this on purpose?
他想伤害我
He wants to hurt me.
那我怎么会有危险
And how am I in danger?
他会杀掉调查他的警察
He murders the loved ones of any cop
心爱的人
who investigates him.
迄今为止  他就是这样逃脱制裁的
It's how he's been able to get away with it so far.
所有追查他的人
Anyone who comes after him,
都会被他杀掉心爱的人
he's killed someone they love
调查也就不了了之了
and the investigation's been buried.
布洛克认识的一个警察
Bullock knows a cop--
回到家时  发现自己的妻子
came home and found his wife.
被割喉了
Her throat had been cut.
所以洛布把这案子交给我
That's why Loeb gave me the case.
要么我像其他人一样放弃调查
Either I give up, like everyone else...
带着放走凶手的愧疚活着
and live, knowing I let a killer go free...
要么我继续调查
or I keep on,
而我心爱的人将遭毒手
and someone I love is killed.
你是不会放弃的  是吗
You're not giving up, are you?
我不能放弃
I can't.
所以你得马上离开哥谭
That's why I need you to get out of Gotham right now.
今晚就走
Tonight.
不行
No.
你想保护我吗  那就把他找出来
You want to protect me? Find him.
我会留在这里  继续工作
I'm gonna stay here and do my job.
但是我很高兴你把我当做是心爱的人
But I do like that you think of me as a loved one.
我的确
I do.
爱你
Love you.
只有连环杀手才让你说出了这句话
And it only took a serial killer to get you to say that.
-谢谢  -没事
- Thanks. - Yeah.
就是这里
This is it.
温馨的家
Home sweet, you know.
这地方很不错
This is a great space.
塞琳娜
Selina?
算是我的室友吧
Sort of a roommate.
她不总在这儿住
She comes and goes.
韦恩集团慈善舞会
Wayne Enterprises Charity Ball.
你不知道我是个名媛吗
Didn't you know I'm a member of society?
我每年都去
I go every year.
穿着漂亮的裙子拍些美照
Get my picture taken in a pretty dress.
摆上笑容
Smile.
我在这儿  你不担心吗
Aren't you scared of my being here?
我该担心吗
Should I be?
你是危险人物吗
Are you dangerous?
不好说  你男友会回来吗
I don't know -- is your boyfriend gonna come home?
我没说过我有男友啊
I never said I had a boyfriend.
你这么美丽  我以为...
I assumed a woman as beautiful as you...
你以为我一定有男友
You assumed I had a boyfriend
而且你还以为我是那种
and you assumed I would be the kind of woman
会背叛他的女人
who would cheat on him.
我不是
Well, I'm not.
而且我也没男友
And I don't have a boyfriend.
就算我明天被车撞死
And if a bus hit me tomorrow,
也不会有人在意
no one would care.
你改主意了吗
That change things?
事实上  确实
Yes, actually, it does.
因为那样会更刺激吗
Make it more illicit?
还是那样我们更不容易建立感情
Or would there be less chance of us getting attached--
一夜风流  再不相见
one night and done.
不过本来也会如此
Only that would happen anyway.
因为一旦你看清了真实的我
Because once you saw the real me,
就会尖叫着逃跑  和其他人一样
you would run screaming, like everyone else.
我得说  你和我想象的很不一样
I have to say, you're not who I imagined you'd be.
惊喜吧
Surprise.
自己走吧  不送了
You can let yourself out.
爱情  爱情*
*Love, love
爱情*
*Love...
爱情  爱情*
*Love, love
爱情*
*Love...
你可是答应和我跳支舞的
But you promised to dance with me.
我会的
And I will.
等我先和那位先生谈完公事
But first I have to finish with that gentleman.
谁知道开个夜店也这么忙呢
Who knew running a nightclub was so much work?
我可怜的小宝贝
My poor darling.
如我所说
As I was saying,
你和你的手下是这里最棒的杀手
you and your crew are the best gun and knife men in the city.
你们刺杀了克莱因议员
Your hit on Councilman Klein--
真是杰作
a thing of beauty.
-我很崇拜你们  -谢谢
- And I'm a fan, so... - Cheers.
你想怎样
What do you want?
想让你为我刺杀马罗尼阁下
For you to help me kill Don Maroni
和他所有的副手
and all of his lieutenants.
你搞笑吧
You're having a laugh.
我很认真
I'm fairly certain I'm not.
法尔科内也同意了
And Falcone's good with this?
他会同意的
He will be.
等生米煮成熟饭以后
When it's done.
我谢你了
Thank you.
但还是算了
No, thank you.
那么你是喜欢排第二喽
So you like being number two.
维克多・萨斯在法尔科内那儿总有优先权
Falcone gives Victor Zsasz first dibs on every new contract.
你把他宿敌的尸首带去
You bring him the bullet-riddled corpse of his enemy
就能翻身
and all of that will change.
这是你晋升的机会啊
This is your chance to move up.
你确实是个疯子
You're a mad fella, aren't ya?
好吧
Fair enough.
明天来酒吧
Come by the bar tomorrow.
我们商量一下细节
We'll talk details.
找我什么事  哈维
What's this about, Harvey?
请坐
Have a seat.
这是我搭档吉姆・戈登
This is my partner Jim Gordon.
警探
Detective.
八年前你调查过一宗凶杀案
Eight years ago, you investigated the murder
死者叫朱莉・肯布尔
of a woman named Julie Kemble.
-那是很久以前了  -是食人魔干的
- That was a long time ago. - It was the Ogre.
朱莉・肯布尔是他第一个杀的人
Julie Kemble was his first victim.
但你放弃了调查
But you dropped the investigation,
就因为如此
and because of that,
后来又有11位女性被杀
11 more women have been murdered.
说真的  两位
Seriously, guys, you know...
够了
Stop.
我们也知道食人魔
We also know the Ogre
会杀害追查他的警察的心爱之人
kills the loved ones of the cops that hunt him down.
这也是从你开始的
That pattern started with you.
我们认为你是发现了令他害怕的东西
We think you found something that spooked him.
这是你调查的笔记
Your notes from the investigation.
最后一页
The last page,
有字被抹掉了
something's been scratched out.
我想知道内容
I want to know what.
他杀了我妻子
He killed my wife.
但我还有个女儿  哈维
I still got a daughter, Harvey.
贝丝・都铎
Beth Tudor.
凯瑟琳・伍德
Katherine Wood.
杰西卡・帕克
Jessica Parker.
11位女性
11 women.
每个都是别人的女儿
Each one was someone's daughter.
不能继续下去了
It has to stop.
好吧  我当时正在调查死者的背景
Yeah. I was doing background on the dead girl.
有人跟我说她是上城区
Someone told me she was a nurse
一家私人诊所的护士
for a private medical clinic uptown.
在格兰特和80街街口
It was on Grant and 80th.
好像是整容的
Some cosmetic place.
这事结束之前我们会安排警察保护你女儿
We'll put cops on your daughter until this is done.
那你原谅我了
So you forgive me?
晚上见
I'll see you tonight.
还好吗  谜语哥
How's it hanging, Riddle Man?
我还
Uh, it's hanging...
好
fine.
尼格玛先生
Mr. Nygma,
有事吗
did you need something?
是的
Yes. Uh...
戈登警探让我检查一遍这几桩旧案的
Detective Gordon wanted me to go through the forensic evidence
法医证据
of these old murders.
好的
Okay.
那是瘀伤吗
Are those bruises?
是多尔蒂警官弄的吗
Did Officer Dougherty do that?
他当时生气了  他不是故意的
Um, he was... upset, and he didn't mean to.
是我说话过分了
I-I said some things I shouldn't have, and...
柯林格小姐  这样不对
Miss Kringle, this is not right.
他不能
He can't just...
尼格玛先生
Mr. Nygma,
这不关你的事
it is none of your concern.
我得开始找卷宗了
Now, I-I need to get started on these files, so...
希德・邦德斯洛  操作部主管
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred.
能起来了吗
Should you be up?
谢谢  布鲁斯少爷  我感觉...
Oh, thank you, Master Bruce. I feel...
好多了
I feel much better.
需要点什么吗
Can I get you anything?
其实  需要
Yes, actually.
我要出席今晚的韦恩集团慈善舞会
I've decided to attend the Wayne Enterprises Charity Ball tonight.
所有的高层都会参加
All the senior management will be there,
我觉得应该让人们知道
and I think people should see
公司依然在韦恩家族的领导下
that a Wayne is still at the head of the company.
那我帮你准备套礼服
I shall set your tux out for you.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred...
什么事  布鲁斯少爷
Yes, Master Bruce.
你参军那会儿
Wh-When you were in the army...
有时得杀人  对吗
you had to kill people, right?
是的
Yes.
没错
Yes, I did.
都是不得不做吗
And it was necessary?
我明白了  你听到了我和雷吉
Oh, I see-- so you overheard the conversation
说的一些不该说的话
that Reggie and I had that was best left unsaid.
不过对于你的问题  是的
But in answer to your question, yes.
不得不做
Yes, it was necessary.
失陪一下
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我得去找枚好袖扣了
I better go and find my good cufflinks,
晚上还要出门呢
if we're stepping out.
不用了  你还在恢复期呢
No, but, uh, you're-you're still recovering.
那我就放心让你一个人
What, I'm supposed to let you walk into that nest
入虎穴吗
of vipers on your tod?
晚会上有上百人呢  阿尔弗雷德
There'll be hundreds of people there, Alfred.
我不会有危险的
I won't be in any danger.
话这么说  但我不会让你一个人去的
So you say. But you're not gonna go alone.
我不是一个人
I won't be alone.
我邀请了塞琳娜・凯尔
I've invited Selina Kyle.
塞琳娜・凯尔
Selina Kyle?
去参加韦恩集团的舞会吗
To the Wayne Enterprises Ball?
我明白了
I see.
明白什么了
What do you see?
没什么  我的意思是...
Nothing. I mean, you know... I mean, you're...
你是个健康的小伙子  她是个漂亮的小姑娘
a healthy young lad and she's a very pretty young girl
而且特别喜欢穿皮衣
with a penchant of wearing, well, a little too much leather.
阿尔弗雷德  不是那样的
Alfred, it's not like that.
那是什么
Then what's it like?
那...
Well...
是又怎么样
well, what if it is, huh?
有什么问题吗
What's wrong with that?
完全没有
Absolutely nothing.
那我就在外面车里等你
So, I will wait in the car outside,
你也不会觉得被人盯着了
so you don't feel my watchful eye,
但我不会走远的  有需要随时叫我
but I will be close by, if there needs be.
就这样
That is the deal.
好
Fine.
你能不能让人
Could you call around and send
送礼服和鞋去给她
some dresses and shoes to where she's staying?
这是地址
This is the address.
就是个慈善舞会  阿尔弗雷德
It's a charity ball, Alfred.
我没事的
I'll be fine.
怪}人的  是吧
Freaky, huh?
他们整得连自己都不认识了吧
You wonder how they recognize themselves after.
汤普金斯医生没事啦
Doc Thompkins is fine.
没人敢在警局动她  放松
No one's gonna touch her at the precinct. Relax.
你该明白  她身处险境都是因为我
You do understand it's because of me that she's in danger.
要是出了什么事  那都是我的错
Anything that happens is my fault.
变态狂犯下的罪
You can't hold yourself responsible
你别自己揽着
for the actions of a psychopath.
当然怪我
Sure, I can.
两位警探  我是库什曼医生
Detectives... I'm Dr. Cushman.
有什么能效劳的
How can I help you?
我们在调查一名
We're looking into the murder
叫朱莉・肯布尔的女子的凶杀案
of a woman named Julie Kemble.
八年前她在这里上班
She worked here about eight years ago.
我知道  太可怕了
Of course. Terrible thing.
朱莉是名非常出色的护士
Julie was a talented nurse.
但当时  她才入职没多久
But she'd only just started here when it happened.
推荐她的是我们这儿的一名患者
She'd been recommended by one of our patients.
那名患者是谁
The patient's name?
抱歉  恐怕不能告诉你们
Well, I'm afraid I can't give you that.
我们有保密协议的
Confidentiality.
是吗
Really?
你真要逼我们申请搜查证吗
You're gonna make us get a warrant?
是的
Yes.
我专门给人做假咪咪  但我这人有道德
"I specialize in fake boobs, but I got ethics.
我得看到搜查证
I need a warrant."
我们去找哈克尼斯法官  相信...
We'll talk to Judge Harkness. I'm sure...
那车在警局门口就出现过
That car was in front of the precinct.
吉姆  等等
Jim, wait up.
你确定吗
You sure about this?
是他
It was him.
你看见他的长相了吗
You saw his face?
没  我应该留意是否有人跟梢的
No. I should've been looking for a tail.
他显然在追踪我们的调查
It's obvious he tracks our investigations.
已经通报了车的样子和部分牌照
Called in a description of the car and a partial plate,
但可能作用不大
but I'm not too hopeful.
那下一步呢
So what's the next move?
戈登  有你电话
Gordon, you got a call.
说很紧急
Says it's urgent.
我是戈登
Gordon.
警探
Detective.
刚刚在巷子里我还没来及跟你好好打招呼呢
I didn't get a chance to say hello properly in the alley.
-听着...  -别想追踪号码了  我就说完
- Listen to me... - Don't bother tracing this. I won't be long.
我就给你一次自首的机会
I'm giving you one chance to turn yourself in.
一旦我去抓你  你就没好果子了
You make me come after you, and I will put you down.
我怎么觉得你相信了报纸对你的吹捧  警探
Something tells me you've begun to buy your own press, Detective.
英雄警探  肃清哥谭
The hero cop who's gonna clean up Gotham.
哥谭市警局崛起的新星
The rising star of the GCPD.
我会阻止你的  我发誓
I'll stop you, that's for damn sure.
不  警探  你不会的
No, Detective, you won't.
你要是还不放手
But keep on your present course,
我就杀死你心爱的人
and I will kill someone you love.
这是我对你唯一的警告
This is your only warning.
天呐
Oh, no.
告诉我那不是他
Tell me that wasn't him.
他一直恐吓警察
He's used to intimidating cops.
我们得让他知道我们不怕他
We have to show him we're not afraid.
那要怎么做
And how do we do that?
你不介意吗  你确定
You're okay with this? You're sure?
是的
Yes.
这是应该做的
It's the right thing to do.
我今天叫你们来
I called you here today...
是因为哥谭市人民有权知道
because the people of Gotham deserve to know
有个连环杀手生活在他们之中
that there's a serial killer in their midst.
多年来  他肆意杀人
For years, he's killed with impunity,
警察的沉默和恐惧助长了他的气焰
aided by a culture of silence and fear among the police.
现在要结束了
That ends now.
我们会提供所有被害人的名字和照片
We'll be providing the names and photos of all of the victims.
请致电提供线索
Please call with any information.
而对于那个犯下了这些可怕罪行的人
And to the man who committed these horrific crimes,
你躲藏的日子结束了
your days of hiding are over.
我要追捕你
I'm coming after you.
我绝不会罢手
And I'm not gonna stop.
这都是干吗的
What are those for?
韦恩慈善舞会
The Wayne Charity Ball.
挺无聊的  但是对画廊生意有好处
It's boring but good for the gallery's business.
那我们在那里见了
Well, I'll probably see you there.
什么
What?
我要和布鲁斯・韦恩一起去
I'm going with Bruce Wayne.
等下  什么
Wait, what?
塞琳娜・凯尔的快递
Delivery for Selina Kyle.
放那里
Uh, over there.
谢谢  请用
Thank you. Enjoy.
我真的要穿这个吗
Am I really supposed to wear these?
好吧
Okay...
咱们有很多活儿要干
we have a lot of work to do.
知道了
Got it.
是那个医生
That was the doctor.
哈克尼斯送去了搜查令
Harkness sent over the warrant.
被杀女孩是一位
The dead girl came to the clinic
康斯坦丝・范・格鲁特女士推荐去的
by way of a Miss Constance van Groot.
范・格鲁特  哥谭最高古老的家族之一
Van Groot-- that's one of Gotham's oldest families.
-做航运的  -没错
- Shipping. - Yeah.
我们认为食人魔是富家子弟
We thought the Ogre might be rich.
也许那老妇人有个儿子
Could be the old lady had a son.
你搞到地址了吗
You got an address?
就在这儿
Right here.
布奇  康纳和他的人同意了
Well, Butch, Connor and his crew are on board.
他们比我还恨马罗尼
They hate Maroni even more than I...
闭嘴  马罗尼和他的人来了
Shut up. Maroni and his crew are here.
我没法赶走他们
I couldn't turn 'em away.
-不  当然  没事  -不是
- No, of course. No matter. - No.
她当时已经到了
She was already here.
那不是我好兄弟奥斯瓦尔德吗
Is that my buddy Oswald?
过来
Come here.
奥斯瓦尔德
Oh, Oswald.
他来了
There he is.
母亲  你在干什么
Mother, what are you doing?
我在喝酒  和这位马...
I'm having a drink with Mr. Mar...
我说了  叫我萨尔
I told you-- Sal.
和萨尔
With Sal.
我们还是别再叨扰...
But we shouldn't impose any longer...
不行  你休想带走我的格特鲁德
No, you're not taking my Gertrud.
他的格特鲁德
Oh, his Gertrud.
坐吧  一起喝点
Sit. Join us.
奥斯瓦尔德  坐吧
Oswald, sit.
坐下  奥斯瓦尔德
Sit, Oswald.
你好
Hello.
我是布鲁斯・韦恩
I'm Bruce Wayne.
芭芭拉・基恩
Barbara Kean.
塞琳娜没提过她和你一起住
Selina never said you're who she's staying with.
戈登警探提到过你
Detective Gordon spoke of you.
塞琳娜有时候戒心很强
Well, Selina can be a little guarded.
是啊  我知道
Yes, I know.
别再议论我了
Stop talking about me.
塞琳娜
Selina.
你看起来很漂亮
You look very nice.
这鞋真疼
The shoes hurt.
玩得开心
Have fun.
到舞会上找我
Look for me at the ball.
很高兴认识你
It was nice meeting you.
你觉得她在这儿吗
Think she's here?
范・格鲁特女士
Miss Van Groot!
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
我得说  这不太合法
I need to say this is not exactly legal.
我们没时间了
We're running out of time.
这边
Over here.
他没事
He's good.
叫支援  我去搜查房子其它地方
Call it in. I'm gonna go check the rest of the house.
他告诉我了...
He told me...
但是我太慢了
but I was too slow.
有人吗
Hello?
范・格鲁特女士
Miss Van Groot?
我是一名警官
I'm a police officer.
范・格鲁特女士
Miss Van Groot?
戈登
Gordon!
吉姆
Jim!
吉姆・戈登
Jim Gordon,
这位是康斯坦丝・范・格鲁特
Constance Van Groot.
所有人都在盯着我们
Everyone's staring at us.
我是布鲁斯・韦恩嘛
Well, I am Bruce Wayne.
我就是嘛
Well, I am.
话说  我没看到邦德斯洛
Anyway, I don't see Bunderslaw anywhere.
也许他不会来了
He's probably not coming.
但是他在宾客名单上
But he's on the guest list.
继续跳舞就是了
Just keep dancing.
或许可以笑一笑
And smile, maybe?
名叫雅各布・斯科林斯基
Name's Jacob Skolimski.
他什么都不说  不过我们知道
He's not talking, but near as we can tell
他曾是老妇人的管家
he was the old lady's butler.
你觉得食人魔是这人的儿子
And you're thinking the Ogre's this guy's son,
而不是死掉的女人的吗
not the dead woman's?
是的  验尸官说老妇人死了好多年了
Yeah, yeah. Coroner said the old bird's been dead for years.
我猜  食人魔杀了她  爸爸假装她还活着
My guess, Ogre killed her, daddy pretends she's still alive,
这样疯子连环杀手儿子可以继续花她的钱
so crazy serial killer son can keep living off her money.
他企图自杀
He tried to kill himself.
他知道你们要找到他了
He knew you were closing in.
-他肯定是跟儿子有联络的  -是啊
- He has to be in contact with his son. - Yeah.
戈登对这事很在意  警监
Listen, Gordon's running pretty hot on this one, Cap.
能怪他吗
Can you blame him?
他认为汤普金斯会是下个目标
Thinks Thompkins is the next victim.
不管怎样  盯着他点
Still, watch him.
阿尔瓦雷斯打来了
Alvarez called.
系统里查不到他儿子的资料
Nothing on the son in the system.
得撬开他的嘴
We have to make him talk.
别折腾了
Make this simple.
说出你儿子的名字和住址
Give us your son's name and address.
否则呢
Or what?
我不怕你
I'm not afraid of you.
那是因为你不了解我
Only because you don't know me.
听着  我理解你想保护儿子
Listen, I get wanting to protect your son,
但还要等他杀掉多少女人
but how many more women is he gonna have to kill
你才会明白  他该被关起来
before you realize he needs to be locked up?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
别跟我装傻  你在楼上
Don't play dumb with me. You were hiding
藏一具烂尸体藏了那么多年
a rotting corpse upstairs for years,
还非要坚持你儿子是天使吗
but no, no, my son's an angel,
还非要说他没杀
he didn't murder close to
近12个女人吗  这还是我们知道的
a dozen women that we know of.
我儿子
My son--
他犯了一个错误
he made one mistake.
就一个
One.
其他的都是谎言
Anything else is lies.
那说实情听听
So tell us the truth.
塞琳娜  昨晚的事
Selina, what happened last night--
那绝不能再发生了
that can never happen again.
我说了  我当时别无选择
I told you I didn't have a choice.
这我不接受
I don't accept that.
我就知道你会受不了
I knew you wouldn't be able to handle it.
你说得对  我当时是想杀他
You're right. I did want to kill him.
小点声
Keep your voice down.
但有道界线  塞琳娜
But there's a line, Selina.
你可以说我是胆小  但事实就是
And you can say I don't have guts, but the fact is
我绝不会跨过那道线
I will never cross it.
那这就是我们的不同了
I guess that's where we're different, then.
因为如果我还要再做一次  我也会做的
'Cause if I had to do it again, I would.
而且我丝毫不会介意
And it wouldn't bother me one bit.
那是邦德斯洛
That's Bunderslaw.
谜语哥
Riddle Man.
多尔蒂警官  能说句话吗
Officer Dougherty, a word.
我可以挑起或终结战争
I can start a war or end one.
我可以给你力量  让你成为英雄
I can give you the strength of heroes
也可以让你无力
or leave you powerless.
只要一瞥  就能诱走我
I might be snared with a glance,
但却没什么能逼我驻留
but no force can compel me to stay.
我是什么
What am I?
猜不到
Got me.
是爱
Love.
柯林格小姐给了你她的爱
Miss Kringle has given hers to you.
而你却回以伤害
And in return, you hurt her.
我看到了她的伤痕
I saw the bruises.
怎么了
And?
你不能那么做
And you cannot do that.
你下次再这样  我就...
The next time you do that, I'll...
冷静
Calm down.
别抽过去了
You'll give yourself a girly fit.
你跟女人处过吗
Have you ever been with a woman?
我猜就是
Didn't think so.
她们就需要管教
They need a firm hand.
尤其是柯林格
That goes double for Kringle.
那丫头嘴巴挺厉害
Girl's got a tongue.
我不会允许你伤害她的
I won't let you hurt her.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你能怎么样
What are you gonna do?
我猜到了
That's what I thought.
回见了  谜语哥
Later, Riddle Man.
愿意跳支舞吗
Care to dance?
-你啊  -是啊
- You. - Me.
小孩子不该在这种地方长大
It was not a place for a boy to grow up.
范・格鲁特女士过着与世隔绝的生活
Miss van Groot kept herself sealed off from the world,
但她十分宠爱我儿子
but she doted on my son.
视如己出
Treated him as her own.
但是
Still, I...
我并不知道他们的感情多深
I didn't realize how deep it went.
这孩子的亲生母亲不在身边
This kid's own mom was out of the picture,
所以他开始认为
so it seems he started thinking
他其实是这位范・格鲁特女士的私生子
he was this van Groot woman's secret son.
我想跟他解释事情不是那样的
I tried to tell him it wasn't true,
但他构造了一个幻想
but he had built this fantasy, and...
范・格鲁特女士也怂恿了这种想法
Miss van Groot led him on.
她是个疯女人
She was deranged.
甚至很残忍
Cruel, even.
于是大概十年前  他找她对质
So, about ten years ago, he confronts her,
要求她认他
he demands that she acknowledge him,
让他用她的姓氏  把他写进遗嘱
give him her last name, put him in the will.
她嘲笑了他
She laughs at him,
说那都是个玩笑
said it was all just a big joke.
于是他就杀了她
So he kills her.
他父亲觉得愧疚  就帮他掩盖
His dad feels guilty, helps him cover it up.
老妇人拒绝了他
So the old woman rejects him,
他就杀了她  从此成了连环杀手
he kills her-- bang, you got a serial killer
一心纠结于母亲的拒绝
with a "mommy didn't love me" complex.
但还有个转折
But there's a wrinkle.
我不知道我儿子在哪
I don't know where my son is.
他今天打给了我  说警察会找上门
He called me today, told me the police would be coming.
但自从他杀了
But I haven't seen him
范・格鲁特女士  我就再没见过他了
since the day he killed Miss van Groot.
我儿子不是个坏人
My son is not a bad man.
你儿子这十年来一直在勾引
Your son has been seducing and killing women
并杀害女人
for almost a decade.
他笑什么
Why is he laughing?
我儿子
My son...
勾引女人
seducing women?
我给你看看我儿子吧  两张照片
Oh, let me show you my son-- two pictures.
我就保存下这点
It's all I managed to save.
听说过"只有亲娘才会爱的脸"吗
You've heard "a face only a mother could love"?
他的亲娘却不爱他
Well... his mother couldn't.
他一出生她就抛下了我们
She left us after he was born.
是啊  我儿子  还引诱女人呢
Oh, yes... my son, the seducer.
所以也怪不得
Now you can see why it makes sense
他把照片里的自己都刮掉了
he scratched his face out of those pictures.
但这样他就不可能是食人魔了
But that means this can't be the Ogre.
我们找错人了
We're chasing the wrong guy.
吉姆有个想法
Jim had an idea.
哈克尼斯法官签的搜查证内容很具体
Judge Harkness's warrant was very specific.
我什么都不用说
I don't have to say anything.
那就点头
Then nod.
你是否给此人做过手术
Did you operate on this man?
我需要知道他如今的模样
I need to know what he looks like now.
否则他下一个杀的女人就怪你了
Or the next woman he kills will be on your head.
他从来
Never, never,
不肯跟其他孩子玩
would he play with the other children.
就是那时候
You know, even then,
他也是鹤立鸡群
he was too good for them.
如今  他是令人尊敬的商人
And now, he is a respectable man of business--
我的奥斯瓦尔德
my Oswald.
嗯
Well...
今晚真是愉快
this has been a delight.
但已经很晚了
But it's late.
有件事
One thing...
格特鲁德  亲爱的
Gertrud, my love.
有个问题一直在困扰我
A question that's been bothering me.
不不  真糟糕
Oh, no. Oh... no, no.
你是在演戏吗
Is this an act?
你是在假装他只是个夜店老板吗
Are you pretending that he's just a nightclub owner?
还是说你真就那么傻
Or are you really that stupid?
住口
Stop!
我不明白
I don't understand. I...
-你儿子  -马罗尼阁下  我警告你
- Your son... - Don Maroni, I am warning you!
是个冷血疯子
is a cold-blooded psychopath.
不不
No, no, no, no, no...
我都数不过来他杀了多少人了
I can't count how many men he's killed.
我的好朋友  弗兰基・卡彭
My own friend, Frankie Carbone,
被他捅了十几刀
he stabbed him a dozen times.
什么样的人会拿刀
What kind of person plunges a knife
一遍遍捅人啊
into someone over and over?
他是个臭骗子  母亲
He is a filthy liar, Mother!
他就是气我耍了他
He's just angry because I played him for a fool!
奥斯瓦尔德
Oswald...
你知道的吧
You know, don't you?
我看得出来
Oh, I can see it.
放开她
Let go of her!
你是不是哪天晚上
Did you catch him, one night,
碰见他洗掉手上的血迹了
washing the blood from his hands?
你是什么时候意识到  自己生了个禽兽的
When did you realize that you had given birth to a monster?
你会为此付出代价的
You are going to pay for this!
或许吧
Maybe.
也或许  结局会是
Or maybe this ends with
我把你了无生气的尸体丢进河里
me dumping your lifeless body into the river.
不管怎样  你和你妈都可以别再装了
Either way, you and Momma Gertrud can stop pretending.
这地方看上去不错
Place is looking good.
那天晚上  你看到我的请帖时
The other night, when you saw my invitation,
为什么不告诉我你也要来
why didn't you tell me you were coming?
我当时没要来
I wasn't.
我并没受到邀请
I didn't get invited.
那么你是不请自来喽
Oh, so you're crashing.
不是  我在宾客名单上的
Oh, no, I'm... on the list.
一万元的捐款能做到很多事呢
It's amazing what a $10,000 donation will do.
你为这场舞会捐了一万元
You donated $10,000 to this?
为什么
Why?
我还希望我的目的不言自明呢
I was hoping that would be apparent.
如果我不来了呢
And what if I decided not to come?
那我就为慈善事业慷慨解了囊
Well, then, I'd have been making a generous donation to charity,
但也会很失望
and I would've been very... disappointed.
昨晚弄成那样
The way things ended last night,
都怪我
it was my fault.
但我对你有种感觉
But I felt something.
我不能就那么放手
I couldn't let it slip away.
这话很动听  但是
Well, that's very sweet, but...
你说  人们如果看清了真实的你
You said that when people see the real you,
就会尖叫着逃跑
they run screaming.
也有人曾这么说我
Someone said the same thing to me once,
说没人会爱我
that no one would ever love me.
谁
Who?
我把她视作母亲的人
The woman I thought was my mother.
芭芭拉
Barbara...
我知道那种感觉
I know what it's like...
内心是一个人
to be one person on the inside,
世界却看到另一副面目
and have the world see another.
我曾那样生活
I lived like that.
这差点摧毁了我
And it almost destroyed me.
我看得出  这在摧毁你
I can see it destroying you.
我不想再跳了
I don't want to dance anymore.
如今的我  是我自己创造的
The person that I am now, I created.
他是我打造出来的
I brought him into being.
我也可以帮你重生
I can do the same for you.
你难道不厌倦伪装吗
Aren't you tired of playing games?
还有隐藏
Of hiding?
是啊
Yes.
-再见  -回头见
- Good-bye. - See you soon.
你好  我是布鲁斯・韦恩
Hello. I'm Bruce Wayne.
希德・邦德斯洛
Sid Bunderslaw.
我在到处走动
I'm going around,
想认识一下所有公司的人
trying to get to know everybody who works for the company.
你是韦恩集团的人吧
You do work for Wayne Enterprises, don't you?
是的
I do.
我是操作部主管
I'm the Director of Physical Operations.
恐怕这工作是很无聊的
Which, I'm afraid, is a bit dull.
这里有很多比我有趣得多的人呢
There are many much more interesting people here.
嗯  我肯定能把大家都认识一遍的
Ah, yes, well, I'm sure I'll get to meet everyone, eventually.
失陪了  布鲁斯
If you'll forgive me, Bruce,
我明早还有很早的航班要赶
I have an early flight tomorrow.
认识你很高兴
It's been a pleasure.
是啊
It was, um...
认识你很高兴
it was nice meeting you.
抱歉
Sorry.
瞧见没
See?
轻而易举
Nothin' to it.
怎么了
What is it?
没什么
Nothing.
站住  混蛋
Stop right there, buster!
谜语哥
Riddle Man?
你偷偷摸摸在这里干什么呢
What the hell are you doing, creeping around here?
你得离开柯林格小姐
You need to leave Miss Kringle alone.
什么
What?!
我不会允许你伤害她的
I'm not gonna let you hurt her.
再也不行了
Ever again.
我认为你该离开哥谭
I think you need to leave Gotham...
就今晚
tonight.
我明白了
I get it now.
你是喜欢上我女人了
You got a thing for my girl.
太有意思了
That's too funny.
别往心里去
Don't take this personal.
还想再挨吗
You want some more?
起来吧
Upsi-daisy...
天呐
Oh, dear.
谜语哥
Riddle Man...
天呐
Oh, dear.
不
Oh, no.
天呐
Oh, dear.
Oh, dear...
奥斯瓦尔德
Oswald.
好点了吗
Feeling better?
我泡了茶
I made tea.
恐怕你
I'm afraid you had...
是...
well...
喝多了
a little too much to drink.
马罗尼先生  他...
Mr. Maroni, he...
他的幽默感很特别
he has a strange sense of humor...
奥斯瓦尔德
Oswald...
我不是乡下来的土包子
I am not some bumpkin from the country,
脑子里装的也不是稻草
with hay in my brains!
当然
No...
我是你母亲
I am your mother...
不管怎样  我都会爱你
and I will love you, no matter what.
但你现在对我撒谎
But lie to me now...
你会伤透我的心
you will break my heart.
奥斯瓦尔德
Oswald...
你有没有做过
have you done things...
你不该做的事
you should not?
我
I...
母亲
Mother...
我是个夜店老板
I'm a nightclub owner.
仅此而已
That's all.
我累了
I'm tired now.
I'm tired.
给格特鲁德的花  萨尔送的
Yeah, I got a delivery for Gertrud, from Sal.
没给小费
Tip's not included.
告诉萨尔  都结束了
You tell Sal it's over.
枪已经买好
The guns are bought.
杀戮室在等着他
The killing room is waiting.
他还不自知  但他死定了
He doesn't know it, but he's a dead man.
算了
On second thought...
我还是亲自告诉他吧
I'll tell him myself.
奥斯瓦尔德
O-Oswald?
是谁啊
Who was that?
是隔壁的雅斯科先生
It's Mr. Yatsko, from next door.
他需要人帮他倒垃圾
He needs help taking out some trash.
那你帮帮他啊
You, you... please, you help him, then.
杰森・范・格鲁特
Jason van Groot?
他本名是杰森・斯科林斯基
His real name is Jason Skolimski.
他去诊所时用的是老妇人的姓氏
He used the old woman's name when he went to the clinic.
但按两个姓氏在哥谭都查不到人
But there's no Jason van Groot or Skolimski in Gotham.
这人就是个鬼魂
The guy's a ghost.
那老妇人拒绝了他  他去找医生
So, the old woman rejects him, he goes to the doctor,
给自己整了张俊脸
gets himself a pretty new face.
在那儿遇到了护士
That's where he runs into the nurse.
开始了疯狂杀人
And we're off to the races.
你们拿到照片了吗
I don't suppose you got a picture.
档案里的丢了  毫不奇怪
Missing from the file. No surprise there.
但好心的医生给我们做了画像
But the good doctor was kind enough to do a sketch.
他已经十年没见过他了
It's been ten years since he last saw him,
但这多少是个开始
but at least it's a start.
我们知道他的真名
So we have his real name,
却不知道他在用什么假名
but not what alias he's using,
除了张时隔十年的画像  也不知道他的样子
or what he looks like beyond a decade-old sketch.
他今天打电话来时说过什么吗
Did he say anything else on the phone today?
任何我们可能漏掉的
Anything we might've missed?
没有  他就是警告我放弃
Nah, just warned me to back off.
叫我别信了报上对我的吹捧
Told me not to believe my own press
说我是哥谭市警局的崛起新星
as the rising star of the GCPD.
怎么了
What is it?
说这话的报纸
The paper that said that--
刊登了一张我在慈善晚会上的老照片
they ran an old photo of me, from a charity gala.
我跟人的合照
I wasn't alone.
芭芭拉
Barbara!
芭芭拉在吗
Is Barbara here?
不在  怎么了
No. Why?
她人呢
Where is she?
你最后见到她是什么时候
When's the last time you saw her?
在韦恩舞会上  她跟个男人走了
At the Wayne Ball. She left with some guy.
是这人吗
Was this the guy?
这画真垃圾
It's kind of a crappy drawing.
是不是他
Was this the guy?
嗯  好像是
Yeah, I think so.
怎么了  他是谁
Why? Who is he?
那里面是什么
What's through there?
自己去看看吧
See for yourself.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com